<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akhil Bhartiya</title>
    <link>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Akhil Bhartiya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:57:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detection and estimation of orbital parameters of an exoplanet</title>
      <link>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/posts/exoplanet_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:57:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/posts/exoplanet_detection/</guid>
      <description>Exoplanets: A World Beyond Our Solar System Detecting exoplanets can be a challenging task and we often have to rely on their heavier and brighter counterparts to detect the presence of planets. Most exoplanets are found through indirect methods: measuring the dimming of a star that happens to have a planet pass in front of it, called the transit method, or monitoring the spectrum of a star for the tell-tale signs of a planet pulling on its star and causing its light to subtly Doppler shift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This &amp;ldquo;About Me&amp;rdquo; page is just to follow the pattern of all the other random personal webpages on the internet. Right now, I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like sharing much. Perhaps another time when I naturally decide to write something about myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>I do not own any social media accounts (except LinkedIn, which I open rarely). I prefer email or phone calls. While I would feel uncomfortable posting my phone number on the internet for everyone to see, I am happy to provide my email address.&#xA;—&#xA;Email: 1729absr@gmail.com&#xA;—</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Likes</title>
      <link>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/likes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/likes/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer : My recommendation of a book or paper doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean that I&amp;rsquo;ve read them completely; it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite unlikely.&#xA;To Read Books Measurement, Paul Lockhart The Principles of Quantum Mechanics, P.A.M. Dirac The Theory of Heat Radiation, Max Planck The Road to Reality, Roger Penrose Surely You’re Joking, Mr. Feynman!, Richard Feynman. If you are reading this book, you should also read the Caltech Letters article: Feynman, Harassment, and the Culture of Science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilbhartiya.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
